Joshua McKendall

Joshua McKendall

4110 Clematis St. New Orleans, LA 70122

Phone: 504.722.8741

Email: joshuamckendall@gmail.com

Portfolio: https://joshuamckendall.github.io Github: https://github.com/JoshuaMckendall

Skills

Fluent in various scripting/programming languages. Proficient in HTML, CSS, Javascript, PHP, SQL, and Ruby. Experienced with multiple libraries including, but not limited to: jQuery, Angular, Bootstrap, Backbone, Rails.

Experience developing for and maintaining Wordpress installations, virtual private servers (mainly linux), and server applications that integrate with SQL databases. Familiarity with DigitalOcean, Amazon Web Services, and CPanel.

Skilled with the Adobe creative suite. Primarily Photoshop, Illustrator, and InDesign.

Experience

Freelance / Full Stack Web Developer

September 2016 - August 2017

Building server-side software applications using the Ruby programming language, and the Rails framework. Using various Javascript libraries on the front-end such as jQuery, Backbone, and Handlebars.

Gameloft New Orleans / Concept Artist Intern

September 2013 - January 2014

Created the look and feel of a character or an asset for a game. Worked with other concept artists and 3d modelers to develop a unique visual aesthetic that was entertaining and tied in thematically with the rest of the game(s).

Education

Tulane University / Bachelor of Science

Major: Applied Computing & Information Systems

Minor: Graphic Design

January 2011 - April 2016, 6823 St. Charles Avenue, New Orleans, LA 70118

Relevant Courses:

- Digital Imaging
- Graphic Design
- Website Development
- Database Fundamentals
- Relational Database Design & Development